<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Moneycurves Investment Analytics</title><description>Thoughts on investment, money and markets.</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><generator>Ghost 0.8</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 06:28:16 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>Thoughts on Economic Impact of India's Monetary Demonetization</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Prime Minister and his team have embarked on a path-breaking move to weed out multiple corruption, black money, counterfeiting of currency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an attempt to structure my thoughts, and capture them for future review. This is a very preliminary analysis, and I am sure, some of the assumptions would&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/welcome-to-ghost/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">7347339b-f199-4261-bfe3-3d7739312b09</guid><dc:creator>Naresh Katariya</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 23:25:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Prime Minister and his team have embarked on a path-breaking move to weed out multiple corruption, black money, counterfeiting of currency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an attempt to structure my thoughts, and capture them for future review. This is a very preliminary analysis, and I am sure, some of the assumptions would not sound smart in weeks to come, as the economic picture unfolds:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Short-term Impacts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stimulus&lt;/strong&gt;: Assuming that 20-25% of "conversion" of 500 &amp;amp; 1000 notes happen via people who do not own the currency, and assuming an 8-10% conversion commission, about Rs. 25000 to 35000 Cr will be "earned" by people at the lower end of economic pyramid, in the coming few weeks. This would be equivalent to a massive economic stimulus. This is expected to be spent quite soon, and predominantly on essential items.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic slowdown&lt;/strong&gt;: There is a sharp ongoing slowdown in consumer spending. This should, of course, start easing as cash starts moving into the system. But it is likely that it would take several months for demand to normalize. And for some sectors whose spending origin is from black money (like luxury retail for example), the damage may be permanent.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Working Capital Logjam&lt;/strong&gt;: A significant part of the Indian economy's supply chain is managed with cash payments (even if it is not black economy). Demonetization is leading to dislocation in debtors settlement, leading to slowdown in supply of fresh goods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Medium-term Impacts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pseudo-Tightening&lt;/strong&gt;: Assuming that 20% of the 500/1000 notes do not get into the system for deposit/exchange, it would amount to a "wealth destruction" of about Rs. 3 Lac Cr! This should lead to demand destruction of discretionary items, consumed by people who would lose this large corpus.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real Estate slowdown&lt;/strong&gt;: This sector is notorious for investors "parking/investing" cash as part of the purchase. With lack of cash availability post the demonetization, real estate prices are expected to correct and remain soft. However, expected drop in interest rates could be a driver for long-term demand in real estate.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Increase in Gold demand&lt;/strong&gt;: Not sure if this is temporary, but there has been a surge in people converting black money into Gold/Silver, that too at inflated prices (20 to 25% premium). While Gold is often purchased with black money, demonetization could actually make Gold look more attractive to the unaccounted cash, as Gold/Silver cannot be demonetized/counterfeited!  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drop in Inflation&lt;/strong&gt;: Current drop in demand/business should lead to a drop in inflation, if not a straight temporary deflation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Structural Impacts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Negative-Wealth Effect&lt;/strong&gt;: Apart from the estimated Rs 3 Lac Cr loss of cash, sections of the public will also feel the effect of loss of additional wealth (cash loss, drop in real estate values, drop in stock market valuations etc). This is going to impact consumption, especially in discretionary side. A big plus could be the moderation in vulgar display of wealth in Indian weddings!  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fall in Interest Rates&lt;/strong&gt;: Excess cash with Banks will lead them to invest in Treasuries/Bonds. This should drive interest rates lower which would be a positive for economy in general.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Redistribution of Wealth&lt;/strong&gt;: The bulk of wealth destruction should be for the top-1% rich guys. Demonetization does nothing much to the common man, but the serious dent on the "do-number" rich is a de-facto wealth transfer to the have-nots.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Increasing Share of Formal Economy&lt;/strong&gt;: This should be driven by two factors: a) Challenges which the cash-based businesses are facing, and b) genuine intent of businessmen to reform and move towards formal/cheque-based economy. This should lead to improvement in prospects of genuine businesses.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drop in Corruption&lt;/strong&gt;: Hopefully, the huge challenges currently being faced by traditional hoarders of cash, should lead people to reform and move away from rampant corruption.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clean-up of Electoral Politics&lt;/strong&gt;: Most opposition parties are making hue and cry and are possibly squirming due to the loss of resources they have hoarded. Effect of demonetization should be evident in the curtailment of "resources" of political parties. Hopefully, this leads to long-term clean-up of the extremely dirty scene in electoral politics of India.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, this move reinforces my confidence that India is on the way to achieve its erstwhile glory!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jai Hind.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Google Search Volume in "Manappuram" is Pointing To Robust Customer Addition</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Manappuram is a Gold Finance company with a large retail base of customers. After very strong growth between 2009 and 2011, they suffered de-growth in customer numbers between 2012 and 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last few years have seen company going back to growing its customer base. This started happening even before Gold&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/google-search-volume-in-manappuram-is-pointing-to-robust-customer-addition/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">097c95d2-445d-4ac8-bc61-1710f5556e94</guid><dc:creator>Naresh Katariya</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 06:25:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Manappuram is a Gold Finance company with a large retail base of customers. After very strong growth between 2009 and 2011, they suffered de-growth in customer numbers between 2012 and 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last few years have seen company going back to growing its customer base. This started happening even before Gold Price bottomed in Dec 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This analysis compares the Google Search Volume (for term "Manappuram") with the level of customer additions in Manappuram's Gold Finance business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Trends for "Manappuram" from 2004 till date:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manappuram appears to be doing something right to attract customer interest again (at least, in online). Google Search Volume appears to be in a strong uptrend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-NH_FuROBgPM/V233TxU5SZI/AAAAAAAAC60/G9Z8NOAdcKAoN-nGn80lWrsh8XP8yoZ2gCLcB/s320/Googlr%2BSearch%2BVolume%2Bfor%2BManappuram.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correlation of Google Search Volume with Customer growth:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-qHczuzZYLOA/V2eOjGoPnQI/AAAAAAAAC4U/JHTqWz5liMgvlBYfvLTVZV_5qFN_X1weACLcB/s320/Manappuram%2BGoogle%2BTrends%2Bvs%2BCustomer%2BGrowth_Jun%2B2016.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As can be seen from above picture, the trend of Google Search Volume closely tracks the level of customer addition, through the previous cycle of falling growth, stabilisation and the ongoing phase of growth coming back in customer acquisition. Statistically, Correlation Coefficient for these two series is 0.62, which is significant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Search volume has been especially strong in the last few quarters. This could partly be influenced by their new Online Gold Loan product. Or could be due to some online marketing which Manappuram is doing for its traditional Gold Loan product. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be interesting to compare the Q1 (FY17) customer addition numbers to verify this hypothesis.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>